<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Quang P. Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Quang P. Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting presidential election using Elo Ratings</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/2020/11/07/forecasting-presidential-election-using-elo-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/2020/11/07/forecasting-presidential-election-using-elo-ratings/</guid>
      <description>[Source Code]
The elo rating system is a method developed by Arpad Elo in order to rank players by ability in a zero sum game. Elo has been used in various contexts, most famously the way to rank chess players through the UCSF and FIDE systems. Elo has been used in modern contexts as well, from Tinder to World of Warcraft. A really nice attribute about Elo is that a difference in scores can be translated to a probability, through the formula:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog!</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/2020/11/04/this-is-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/2020/11/04/this-is-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>This is my personal blog! I have decided to attach this to my website since I don’t intend to blog too much outside of some side projects that I have or some random thoughts. I most likely blog about statistics and data science in general! Stay tuned for some pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>Education PhD Candidate in Quantitative Biomedical Sciences, Dartmouth College
Working Thesis Title: A multi-omics approach to assess functional redundancy in infant gut microbiomes
B.S. in Biochemistry and Mathematics, Bates College
Thesis Title: Transcriptomic analysis of the role of transcription factor Nfe2 in zebrafish development
Honors and Awards 2020 NSF DIFUSE Fellow (Data Science Infused Undergraduate STEM Education)
2017 Maine INBRE Summer Research Fellow
Experiences (03/2020 - current) - Data Quality Co-lead &amp;amp; Science Communicator, The COVID Tracking Project at The Atlantic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-academic Writings</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/writings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/writings/</guid>
      <description>Aside from research, I also love to write! I am passionate about science communication, particularly data and numerical literacy. Here are some of my published articles:
The State of State Antigen Test Reportings
By Betsy Ladyzhets and Quang P. Nguyen
The COVID Tracking Project at The Atlantic
Antigen tests are becoming a major tool for rapid COVID-19 testing. But if states don’t report results clearly, we won’t know the true impact of these tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/research/</guid>
      <description>Research topics My research primarily concerns the statistical and bioinformatic analysis of infant gut microbiomes. Some overarching questions include:
 How to define functional redundancy in the context of complex microbial communities. How to leverage external information to perform hypothesis aggregation and variable selection for inferential/predictive tasks relating to microbiome research Multi-omics analysis of the microbiome.  Pre-prints and published manuscripts Multi-omic Characterization of the Taxa-function Relationship in Infant Gut Microbiomes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/software/</guid>
      <description>Eddy Covariance Exploration Shiny App
[Source Code] [Shinyapps.io]
BIOL 16 is a course that examines fundamental concepts in the rapidly developing areas of ecology. As an part of the DIFUSE program funded by NSF at Dartmouth College, we built an interactive data visualization and analysis tool based on R Shiny for students to explore the eddy covariance technique. Students are able to view data in raw format, interact with different visualizations, as well as being able to use such data to learn about how carbon exchange differs between seasons and time of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Projects</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/side-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/side-projects/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday Submissions
[Source Code]
Most recent tweet:
My late #TidyTuesday submission for week 48 of this year! For this hiking dataset I explored (through visualizations) whether the distributions of features differ between high and low rated trails, conditioning on length of trail and summit height (Code: https://t.co/xVPZzER75D) pic.twitter.com/kTTNLucL86
&amp;mdash; Quang Nguyen (@quangpmnguyen) November 27, 2020  Code and graphs for Tidy Tuesday submissions. Tidy Tuesday is a weekly online event hosted by the R4DS community to promote usage of R in data wrangling and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
