<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Quang P. Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Quang P. Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>Education PhD Candidate in Quantitative Biomedical Sciences, Dartmouth College
Working Thesis Title: A multi-omics approach to assess functional redundancy in infant gut microbiomes
B.S. in Biochemistry and Mathematics, Bates College
Thesis Title: Transcriptomic analysis of the role of transcription factor Nfe2 in zebrafish development
Honors and Awards 2020 NSF DIFUSE Fellow (Data Science Infused Undergraduate STEM Education)
2017 Maine INBRE Summer Research Fellow
Experiences (03/2020 - current) - Data Quality Co-lead &amp;amp; Science Communicator, The COVID Tracking Project at The Atlantic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-academic Writings</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/writings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/writings/</guid>
      <description>Aside from research, I also love to write! I am passionate about science communication, particularly data and numerical literacy. Here are some of my published articles:
As North Dakota’s Deaths Metrics Diverge, We’re Switching to a Less Backlogged Measure of Fatalities
By Kara W. Schechtman, Quang P. Nguyen, and Joseph Bensimon
The COVID Tracking Project at The Atlantic North Dakota&amp;rsquo;s growing backlog of death certificates means its count of individuals who died due to COVID is no longer an accurate measure of deaths in the state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/research/</guid>
      <description>Research topics My research primarily concerns the statistical and bioinformatic analysis of infant gut microbiomes. Some overarching questions include:
 How to define functional redundancy in the context of complex microbial communities. How to leverage external information to perform hypothesis aggregation and variable selection for inferential/predictive tasks relating to microbiome research Multi-omics analysis of the microbiome.  Pre-prints and published manuscripts Multi-omic Characterization of the Taxa-function Relationship in Infant Gut Microbiomes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/software/</guid>
      <description>Eddy Covariance Exploration Shiny App
[Source Code] [Shinyapps.io]
BIOL 16 is a course that examines fundamental concepts in the rapidly developing areas of ecology. As an part of the DIFUSE program funded by NSF at Dartmouth College, we built an interactive data visualization and analysis tool based on R Shiny for students to explore the eddy covariance technique. Students are able to view data in raw format, interact with different visualizations, as well as being able to use such data to learn about how carbon exchange differs between seasons and time of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Projects</title>
      <link>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/side-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qpmnguyen.netlify.app/side-projects/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday Submissions
[Source Code]
Most recent tweet:
Week 51 of #TidyTuesday. This week&amp;#39;s data is about the American Ninja Warrior contest! The big attempt this week is the circle plot using #circlize, as well as trying to make the plot less &amp;quot;sad&amp;quot; (i.e. default looking). Code at https://t.co/ygWCaKoC5d pic.twitter.com/7myUyCmyck
&amp;mdash; Quang Nguyen (@quangpmnguyen) December 18, 2020  Code and graphs for Tidy Tuesday submissions. Tidy Tuesday is a weekly online event hosted by the R4DS community to promote usage of R in data wrangling and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
